You think you can win? Hilarious.
勝算？真是可笑
She's quick.
好快
She moves faster than Ushioh, maybe even faster.
她的動作與潮不相上下 不，在潮之上嗎？
Pulling out all the stops for the final battle, Hizuru?
你是下了以命相搏的決心嗎？日鶴
That was a close one. Come on, Shide. Wake up.
好險，喂，紙垂 你要躺到甚麼時候？
Up and at 'em. All right.
唉呀，等等，你手上的…
You're pretty good at handling my sacred treasure, Amenonuboko.
可是我們神社珍貴的寶物天野矛 你用得挺順手的
Ryunosuke is a shadow, after all. He can't copy, but he's good at imitating.
龍之介好歹也是影子，雖說不能複製 但模仿能力還是挺強的
The wrath in each strike is shocking!
每一擊的殺氣都很恐怖啊
I've known you since you were a baby.
真是太打擊了 我可是從小看著你長大的啊
You hate me that much?
你就這麼討厭我嗎？
Why go so far? Why risk your life to fight?
為甚麼要這樣奮戰？ 你拚死戰鬥的意義何在？
What I hate are your words.
我討厭的是你的語言
Words?
語言？
Humans have language. Human nature determines how to use words.
人類擁有語言、詞彙 如何使用語言決定了那個人的人性
You'll never understand, no matter how long you live.
你是無法理解其中的意義的 不管活幾百年都一樣
I have one question for you. Why did you come back, Hizuru?
我再問你一次，為甚麼要回來？日鶴
Only a fool would come only to die. It's not like you.
明知會死還要回來 這是蠢人做的事，一點都不像你
You should know the answer. The last time, you scanned my mind.
你已經知道了吧，上次問我時 應該掃描過我的大腦了
Oh, perhaps it's just beyond your comprehension?
我知道了，你讀取了記憶 卻無法理解嗎？
Why don't you scan me again? Ask my shadow to answer.
再掃描我一次怎麼樣？ 生出我的影子，讓那影子來回答你
I'm not falling for that.
我不會上當的
Hizuru, you must be immune. Mioh could've done that.
日鶴，你有免疫了吧 利用影子澪就可以做到
You just want to destroy this body the moment I flash.
你是打算趁我掃描的時候 破壞我這副身體，對吧？
Is it that obvious?
被發現了嗎？
You think you can defeat Shide if it weren't for my eye.
只要沒有我的眼睛，就能打倒紙垂
Then it would be easy to destroy my real body that's underground.
沒了紙垂 再破壞我在地下的本體就簡單了
Just wait. So answer me! Was it because of the message?
等一下，回答我，為甚麼回來？ 是因為那則訊息嗎？
That's typical of Shinpei Ajiro.
這是網代慎平的人格吧
While stepping back logically, he persists on getting answers.
一方面冷靜地俯瞰事物 卻又無法放下無法理解的事
What's with all this talking?
要繼續和她交談下去嗎？
It's perfect to buy time. Just let me handle it.
這是爭取時間的好機會，交給我
At first, it was curiosity. Now I think I'd been waiting for this.
最初是因為好奇 不過我也一直在尋找…
It's my chance to make it up to him.
贖罪的機會
Make it up to him?
贖罪？
Shide is right. Ryunosuke died because of me.
四手說得沒錯，龍之介的死是我的錯
Ryunosuke's death was treated as an accident.
龍之介的死被當作意外處理了
No one blamed me. My friends and parents consoled me.
沒人責備我，親戚朋友也都來安慰我
I became this pitiful child who lost her twin in an accident.
認為我是在事故中 失去雙胞胎弟弟的可憐孩子
But the truth is, it's as if I killed him.
實際上，他等於是被我殺死的
It was a miracle that I met his shadow, and it let me apologize to him.
後來奇蹟發生 我可以向龍之介的影子道歉
But that doesn't mean he's alive again. There's one thing I can do now.
但是他並沒有活過來 現在的我能做的事
I can at least save the lives that would otherwise be lost.
就只有拯救接下來會失去的生命
Yes.
嗯
So I will save them. I must.
所以我一定要救他們
You want to make it up to him? So that's the reason.
贖罪，這就是你的理由
How pathetic. You risk your life for strangers?
真是噁心，為了毫無關係的人 拚上自己的性命？
I hate people who believe that they're doing the right thing!
自以為正義的人是最麻煩的
The right thing?
正義？
The right thing, you say?
正義，你說我嗎？
You need to step back more, Heine.
喂，再多俯瞰一下吧，波稻
Do you actually think he's acting for your benefit?
那個男人做的事情真的是為了你嗎？
What?
甚麼
Your goal of going home and his words in the third loop contradict.
回你故鄉的目的
You said that it was your ending.
「這就是我的結局」
What did you mean by that, Shide?
那是甚麼意思？四手
Ending?
「結局」？
The man only thinks of himself. He cannot go beyond his own perspective.
那個男人任何時候都只說「我」 永遠只用第一人稱描述事情
Ending, huh? I'm lost.
「結局」？你在說甚麼？
It's nonsense, Heine. She is trying to trick us with words.
一派胡言，波稻 她這是在用語言迷惑我們
Yes.
嗯
That means she has nothing left.
反過來說，她已經無計可施了
Enough of this pleasant conversation.
愉快的談話就到此為止吧
I didn't want Heine to see, but I can't ask for much.
可能的話，我還是不想讓波稻看到 不過如今不能有這種奢侈的想法了
The rest is up to you, Tokiko.
接下來就交給你了，朱鷺子
Shide's armor is no one. It's empty inside.
四手的鎧甲不是任何人，裡面是空的
So...
所以…
You can get inside it.
你應該能入侵進去
Ryunosuke, you know well how to possess people.
這是你擅長的吧？龍之介 附體到別人身上
Get into his armor and destroy it from the inside.
潛入那傢伙的鎧甲中，從內部破壞
What the...
甚麼？
You...
你是…
So this was up your sleeve, Hizuru.
日鶴居然還有這一手
Copying Ryunosuke's data to Shide's armor.
將龍之介的資料列印到紙垂的泥上 用來作為材料…
It's born?
竟然生出來了？
We really did it.
做出來了，真的可以
Sis!
姐姐！
Stand back, Shinpei. It's dangerous.
退後，小慎，危險
I was waiting for you.
真是的，我都等得不耐煩了
Where are Mio and Sou?
澪和窗怎麼樣了？
So you did come see Mio first, Shinpei.
你果然來小澪這邊了，慎平
Stand back, Shinpei, I got him.
都說讓你退後了，小慎，我來動手
Shouldn't you kill Shinpei rather than me, Mioh?
你應該殺了慎平而不是我吧，小澪
I sent Mio and Sou to Hiruko's grotto.
我把小澪和窗送到蛭子洞去了
Mother is probably eating them now.
現在媽媽正在享用吧
You were just a bit too late, Shinpei!
你還是晚了那麼一點點啊，慎平
You have some guts, Shide. You didn't run away.
看來你膽子不小啊，紙垂 不躲也不逃，獨自在這裡等著我們
I can't leave this to other shadows. I don't want to lose any more allies.
不能交給其他影子 畢竟我們不想再失去同伴了
A human like me can't be hacked.
身為人類的我是不會被入侵的
What?
甚麼？
He is afraid of hacking.
他害怕被入侵？
He must think Ushioh is alive.
這傢伙認為潮還活著
What's this?
奇怪
Wait. If he thinks she's alive, I should let him.
等等，既然如此 那就讓他繼續誤會下去
Oh, you got us.
被你看穿了啊
Mioh, kill Shinpei and make him loop, or it will be too late...
小澪，快殺了慎平讓他進入迴圈 否則就快來不及…
Okay. Well, I'll be reborn in the next loop anyway.
對了，只要再進入迴圈，我就會復活
So chatty.
話太多了
Shinpei, what he said was true. Mio just died.
小慎，這傢伙說的是真的 澪剛剛死了
You can tell?
你怎麼知道的？
I can feel if my original dies.
原型一死，我就能感覺到
Want to go back?
要回去嗎？
No. Not yet.
不，還不行
We need to grasp the situation. Search his memories.
我們要掌握情況，調查他的記憶吧
Okay.
好的
Strange. He has no memories.
奇怪，這傢伙沒有記憶
What do you mean?
怎麼會這樣？
There's no memory at all, not even the conversation we just had.
是空的，連剛才和我們對話的記憶 都沒有，這到底是甚麼？
What moved him around?
是怎麼讓他動起來的？
Shide has two bodies then. Not shadows, but cloned humans.
紙垂有兩個，不是影子 是兩個人類，就像克隆體一樣
He didn't have that burn on his arm. There must be another.
這傢伙手上的確沒有燒傷痕跡 那另外一個…
He must be with Ms. Nagumo.
一定就在南雲老師那邊
She must be in danger. Heine called from her phone.
老師可能也出事了 波稻用老師的手機給我打了電話
Shinpei. This way.
小慎，這邊
Tokiko!
朱鷺子
Thank goodness you're alive, Shinpei.
太好了，你還活著，慎平哥
I came this far searching for Mio's presence.
我是循著澪的氣息來到這裡的
Tokiko. What happened?
朱鷺子，發生甚麼事？
Nezu and Totsumura let me escape.
是根津先生和凸村先生幫我逃出來的
Go to Torajima Island. Please.
拜託，虎島…快去虎島
Ryunosuke is fighting Shide.
龍之介先生在和紙垂戰鬥
She's dead.
她死了
These are Tokiko's memories.
這是朱鷺子的記憶
Quickly. Let's go to Torajima Island.
我們快去虎島
It's Dr. Hishigata's Derringer. Tokiko had it.
是菱形醫生的掌心雷 朱鷺子一直帶著嗎？
One bullet left.
還剩一發子彈
Shinpei.
小慎
Okay. I'm not going.
好，我們不去了
Ryunosuke and Ms. Nagumo might be dead. I couldn't tell from Tokiko's memories.
老師和龍之介先生恐怕已經被殺了
I don't have time to go and confirm it.
但我們也沒時間去確認了
We know that Mio is dead. The event horizon is getting closer.
可以確定的是，澪死了 以及事件水平線在逼近
If we don't hurry, Mio's death will be set.
再不快點回去，澪的死就會成為事實 現在還來得及救兩邊
If I loop now, it'll be around 10:10 a.m.
現在馬上進入輪迴 應該能回到10點10分左右
Oh, I was leaving Mt. Takanosu with the kids.
是和孩子們從鷹巢山下山的時候
You can see?
你能看到嗎？
Yes, vaguely.
嗯，雖然很模糊
But I can't stop Heine's call at 10:10 a.m.
不過10點10分時 已經無法阻止波稻打電話了
First, I'll hurry back to Kofune.
我會先以最快的速度回到小舟西餐廳
I have to save you there.
把你救出來
Then I'll go after Mio and Sou to stop them.
再飛速追上澪和窗，攔住他們 回去之後沒時間和你詳細說明了
Follow me. We'll save both Mio and Ms. Nagumo.
你默默跟上來就行 澪和南雲老師，兩邊我都要救
It's a battle against time.
與時間賽跑，對吧？
I'm going now.
那我去了
28 MINUTES AFTER NINTH LOOP START 10:39
（第九輪開始28分鐘後，10點39分）
You guys.
你們…
Why are you here? Shinpei?
怎麼會在這裡？小慎
I made it in time. Mioh ran through the sewers from Kofune to get us here.
趕上了，我讓影子澪走下水道 從小舟一路趕過來的
You saved Mioh?
你救了她嗎？
She's alright.
她沒問題
Why are your phones turned off?
你們兩個的電話是不是關機了？
What?
甚麼？
You told us to turn them off in case a shadow might call.
可是小慎你不是說 影子可能會打電話，讓我們關機嗎？
Fool. That was a shadow telling you.
笨蛋，那電話就是影子打的
Sorry, Shinpei, I should have known.
抱歉，慎平，有我在還是發生這種事
It's okay. We don't have much time. I'll head to Torajima Island with Mioh.
沒甚麼，沒時間了 我和影子澪去虎島
I'm sorry I shot you.
抱歉，我還用槍打你，那個…
It hurt, but it's okay.
雖然很痛，不過沒關係
I just copied you and healed my wounds. It did hurt a lot though.
剛才複製了你，治好了傷 所以沒事了，雖然真的很痛
I'm sorry!
對不起
Don't worry. I would've done the same.
別在意，如果我是你，也會這麼做
Sou and Mio, go back to Kofune and watch the kids.
窗和澪先回小舟西餐廳照顧那些孩子
Leave them to us!
交給我們吧
Shinpei.
小慎
Save Tokiko and the others.
朱鷺子他們就交給你了
Yeah, I got this.
嗯，放心吧
Let's go, Mioh. To Torajima Island.
走吧，澪，去虎島
According to Tokiko's memories,
根據朱鷺子的記憶
Ms. Nagumo sends the signal at 10:45.
南雲老師發出信號的時間是10點45分
TORAJIMA ISLAND
（虎島）
Let me get there in time. Please!
要趕上，我一定要趕上
We don't have time to fight, Mioh.
澪，沒時間戰鬥了
I'll jump. Don't bite your tongue.
我跳過去，別咬到舌頭了
We made it.
到了
That is Shide's attack that I saw in Tokiko's memories!
那是四手的攻擊 和在朱鷺子的記憶中看到的一樣
What did it do? Rose was gone in a second.
那傢伙究竟做了甚麼 一瞬間就把羅斯…
So this is how things can change.
原來如此，原來事情的發展 會變成這樣啊
Rose!
羅斯！
He's here. Quicker than I expected.
來了嗎？比預期的要快啊
Shinpei!
慎平哥
Stand back, Tokiko.
朱鷺子，別出手
You'll die.
會死的
I see. You looped, so you know how this battle ends.
通過輪迴 掌握了這場戰鬥的來龍去脈嗎？
Tokiko must've told you after she escaped.
是逃掉的朱鷺子告訴你的吧？
Oh, why so surprised, Shinpei?
真是的，你在驚訝甚麼？慎平
Because you looped, we got to fight again.
多虧了你的迴圈，我們才能再打一場
No...
怎麼會…
Thanks to you, it was an easy win.
太感謝你了 多虧了你，我們贏得很輕鬆
Ms. Nagumo!
老師
You're too far. Don't waste bullets, Totsumura!
這距離打不中的，別浪費子彈，凸村
What?
甚麼？
Is that Heine? Second time fighting this battle?
那就是波稻嗎？ 那傢伙是第二次經歷這場戰鬥？
After the loop, it knew my attack position. Darn it.
輪迴後知道了我狙擊的位置，該死
We've only got my hatchet, Totsumura's Derringer,
這邊的武器只有我的山刀 凸村的掌心雷
Gil, and Mioh.
基爾，還有影子澪
This isn't going to be pretty if we fight now, Shinpei.
情況不太妙啊，慎平 現在開戰的話…
We're all going to die.
會全軍覆沒的
What?
甚麼？
Shinpei. Mioh. Let's pull back.
慎平、澪，撤退
Get on Gil.
騎到基爾身上
Are you deaf, Shinpei?
沒聽到嗎？慎平
I don't want to leave Ms. Nagumo!
可是老師她… 我們要就這樣丟下老師不管嗎？
Moron! We need to pull back! Don't waste her sacrifice!
笨蛋，所以才要撤退啊 你想讓日鶴白白犧牲嗎？
This is...
這是…
Let's go, Shide.
回去了，紙垂
We're outnumbered. This is enough for now.
我們寡不敵眾，先到此為止
I understand.
好的
W-We're safe.
得救了
Ms. Nagumo! Stay with me!
老師，南雲老師
I-Is that you, Shinpei...
慎平嗎？
Ms. Nagumo.
老師
It was a promise...
我不能…
But I don't think I can keep it.
遵守諾言了
That's not true! Not at all!
怎麼會？沒這回事
Totsumura! Give me the gun!
給我槍，凸村先生
Oh, here!
好
I'm going back.
我現在就回去
No.
住手
I'll save you next time.
下次我一定能救你
Stop. It's too late.
住手，來不及的
You know more than anyone. The loop ability is reaching the limit.
小慎你應該是最清楚的吧 你的輪迴能力已經快到極限了
You can't save both of them.
已經不可能兩邊都救了
We need to take her to the hospital. I'm sure Mioh can...
那就去醫院 有影子澪在，眨眼間就能…
Listen closely.
聽著，給我聽清楚了
Heine is just a child.
那傢伙…波稻是個孩子
She may be a monster,
她也許是個怪物，但最初的人格
She's just a child.
她只是一個孩子
Shide's aim is not the same as Heine's.
紙垂的目的和波稻不同
Heine is probably just being used by Shide.
波稻應該只是被紙垂利用了
Shide is the one in charge.
頭目是紙垂
Shinpei, please free Heine.
慎平，將波稻 從那傢伙的掌控中解放出來吧
I will. I promise.
好，我一定會做到
Enough. Don't talk anymore, Hizuru.
好了，別說話了，日鶴
It's not such a bad way to end.
對我來說這結局還不差
Stop being so gloomy.
別一個個愁眉苦臉的
It doesn't matter how long I've lived...
人重要的不是活了多久
but how I used my life to the fullest.
而是如何讓生命發揮最大的價值
I'm putting my brother in your care.
我的弟弟就託付給你了
What a comeback story this will be.
最後要給我絕地大翻身啊
Hey, Hizuru?
喂，日鶴
Hizuru!
日鶴